

# Patrick Dwyer

Data Scientist at Manifold Group with 1+ years of software development experience. Experience in Software Development, Computer Vision, Time Series Modeling/Forecasting, and DevOps. Strong knowledge of Python, Javascript, and SQL. Interested in building software that improves the world at least a little bit. Based in Saint Louis but open to hybrid positions.

# Experience

### Manifold Group: Data Scientist

- Built CI pipeline for building and publishing back end machine learning and database management services as Docker containers to AWS ECR with GitLab
- Building database management and machine learning backend services in Python and Node.js as Dockerized applications

### Websanity: Web Developer

• Freelance Web Developer for Rulepop, an emerging rules reference platform for tabletop games

#### October 2023 - Present

- Defined postgres database schema in relation to machine learning model requirements and existing data pipeline constraints
- Developing real-time (<30 second response latency) streamed anomoly detection/forcasting models on time series data

#### September 2023 - October 2023

 Implemented search using Fuse.js, page sharing using share api and dynamic title switching for all live rules references

#### **Schwartz Lab:** Lab Tech

- Developed supervised 3d Convolutional Neural Network in
  PyTorch
- Set up extrinsic camera calibration routine by implementing •
  Levenberg-Marquardt for Bundle Adjustment
- Extended PyTorch torch.autograd.Function class to integrate 3d→2d point projection into autograd
  - Manually labelled 8,544 ground truth 2d points using selfmade image labeling program

### Manifold Group: Data Science Intern

July 2022 - March 2023

July 2023 - Sep 2023

- Collaborated with head of data analytics to build a modular and extendable data pipeline in Python using Pandas and NumPy
- Visualized data for head of data analytics and partners using Matplotlib and Altair

### **Technical Skills**

# Languages Tools Libraries

Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS, SCSS, HTML, Bash(Unix shell)

Docker, ECR, Postgres (RDS), Node.js, npm, git, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Tower, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter node:http, node:fs, Fuse.js, NumPy, PyTorch, Matplotlib, Pandas, PySpark, OpenCV, Flask

### **Education**

**BA:** Mathematics, Computer Science

Sep 2019 - June 2023

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL — Weinberg College of Arts and Sciences — 3.43/4.00 GPA

# **Projects**

patrickdwyer.com Summer 2023-Present

Responsive CV website built from scratch using no pre-built libraries and industry best practices